A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Homes, Series I FA318
Rockefeller Archive Center
- House Books
  - 1971 Distribution (by Appraisal Numbers)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book IX: 591-665 (Box 180, Folder 1684)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book X: 666-699 (Box 180, Folder 1685)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book XI: 700-755 (Box 180, Folder 1686-1687)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book XII: 756-820 (Box 180, Folder 1688-1689)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book XII: 756-820 (Box 181, Folder 1690)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book XIII: 821-872 (Box 181, Folder 1691)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book XIV: HC 1-51 (Box 181, Folder 1692-1693)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book XV: HC 52-101 (Box 181, Folder 1694)
    - 1971 Distribution - Parke Bernet Book XVI: HC 102-167 (Box 181, Folder 1695-1696)
    - 1971 Distribution - Silver 168-217 (Box 182, Folder 1697)
      Inventory, pricing, photos, location, description, dimensions and count.
    - 1971 Distribution - China 218-252 (Box 182, Folder 1698)
    - 1971 Distribution - 740 Park Avenue: Summary Linen (Box 182, Folder 1699)
      Full lists of linens arranged by page number, "Old Records" and appraisals.
    - 1971 Distribution - 740 Park Avenue: Silver (Box 182, Folder 1700-1701)
      Inventory, pricing, location, description, dimensions and/or count.
    - 1971 Distribution - 740 Park Avenue: China (Box 182, Folder 1702)
    - 1971 Distribution - X X X (Box 183, Folder 1703)
      Pricing, photos, dates, locations, dimensions, descriptions, handwritten notes.
    - 1971 Distribution - Mysteries (Box 183, Folder 1704)
      Bust and paintings.
  - Lincoln Warehouse, 1960-1964 (Box 183, Folder 1705)
  - Lincoln (Box 183, Folder 1706-1707)
    Price, date, location, description, mounted photos, purchase location, handwritten notes.
  - Distributions: Rugs, Paintings (Box 184, Folder 1709)
    Tab titles include: Vender Weyden, Veneziano, Duccio, Chardin, Nattier, Fragonard, Goya, Botticelli, Burgundians, and Miscelllaneous.
  - Distributions: Rugs, Paintings (Box 183, Folder 1708)
  - By Recipient - Abby Rockefeller Mauze (ARM) (II) (Box 184, Folder 1710)
    Appraisal numbers, pictures, descriptions and supplementary information concerning mirrors, chairs and tables.
  - By Recipient - JDR 3rd (II) (Box 184, Folder 1711)
    Appraisal numbers, pictures, descriptions and supplementary information concerning furniture, paintings, lamps and china.
  - By Recipient - Nelson A. Rockefeller (NAR): Book 1 (Box 184, Folder 1712-1713)
    Appraisal numbers, furniture, paintings and miscellaneous.
  - By Recipient - Nelson A. Rockefeller: Book 2 (Box 184, Folder 1714-1715)
    Rugs, ornaments, lamps, paintings, linens, china, glassware.
  - By Recipient - Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR) (II) (Box 185, Folder 1716)
    Appraisal numbers, rugs, furniture, silver, linen, mirrors, glassware.
  - By Recipient - Winthrop Rockefeller (WR) (II) (Box 185, Folder 1717)
    Appraisal numbers, photos of figurines, mirrors, paintings, furniture.
  - By Recipient - David Rockefeller (DR) (II) (Box 185, Folder 1718)
    Appraisal numbers, photos of furniture and other objects.
  - Distributions: Porcelains (Box 185, Folder 1719-1721)
  - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA) (Box 186, Folder 1722-1723)
    Tab titles include: Folk Art, Sculpture, Sculpture - Metal, Sculpture - Modern, Sculpture - Wood, and Silver.
  - Museums: Brooklyn, Cooper Union, Hispanic Society, Minneapolis Institute of Arts, Rockefeller Institute (Box 186, Folder 1724)
    Distributions to Museums, Societies, and other Institutions.
  - Jewelry (Box 186, Folder 1725-1726)
    Tap titles include: "Clips and Brochures - Dia", "Bracelets - Dia, "Earclips - Dia, Pearl", "Necklaces - Dia, Pearl", "Saphires", "Rubies", "Emeralds - (Alexander II and set)", "Emeralds - Other", and "Following returned for Credit".
  - Negatives, Personal Property at Hillcrest
    The Negatives are individually notated. (For example: each of the negatives has a label with a letter—explained by the key—and a number—to denote each negatives’ place in the original order). The negatives are arranged alpha-numerically by their letter-number designation (for example: A12 precedes B1). There are several alpha-codes within the key that are not represented in the records (for example: there are no negatives labeled “F” which denotes Sofas), nor are the numbers always perfectly sequential (for example: there is no negative in the collection labeled D4, but there is a negative labeled D5). Several negatives may have the same label, but depict different objects (for example: there are four negatives labeled G18). Finally, there are several numbers that are represented by note cards or photographs instead of negatives.
    - Negatives, Personal Property at Hillcrest (Box 186, Folder 1727-1728)
    - Negatives, Personal Property at Hillcrest (Box 187, Folder 1729-1734)
    - Negatives, Personal Property at Hillcrest (Box 188, Folder 1735-1740)
    - Negatives, Personal Property at Hillcrest (Box 189, Folder 1741-1745)
  - Chinese Porcelain: Master Card File (Box 190)
    The Master Card file is comprised of index cards with images and details about John D. Rockefeller Jr’s extensive porcelain collection. A key is available on site at RAC which provides notations used to denote the individual items.
  - Duplicates
    All contents of Box 191 is duplicates of the Eyrie (Seal Harbor, Maine) House Books.
    It is recommended that researchers access the Eyrie House Books, Boxes 164-167.
    - Duplicates - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR): Maine, Porcelains, Bronzes (Box 191)
    - Duplicates - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR): Oriental Rugs, Antique Rugs, Pillows (Box 191)
    - Duplicates - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR): Maine, Iron, Brass, Brocades (Box 191)
    - Duplicates - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR): Furniture, Cabinets, Chairs, Tables (Box 191)
    - Duplicates - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR): Maine, Boxes, Trays, Woodcarvings, Screens (Box 191)
- Oversized
  - Oversized Materials from the Homes Series (Box 174)